







Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Project Management, Client Management, Requirement Gathering, Technical Architecture, Cobol, Endevor, JCL



Total Experience: 11 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers] Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Team Lead/Tech Lead, Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Project Management, Client Management, Requirement Gathering, Technical Architecture, Cobol, Endevor, JCL

Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Having 10 years of Experience in Health Insurance domain.

Technical forte is IBM Mainframes in the areas of Software Analysis, Design, Development, Maintenance and support by using Mainframe Technologies like COBOL, JCL, VSAM, DB2, IMS, DYL280.

Co-ordinated projects on Ab Initio with competent coding knowledge.

Lead the teams across geographies by successfully implementing big size projects. Experienced in Offshore-onshore Operating model.

Involved in technical writing, prepared document of understanding of the Application and Technical Design document.

Strong experience in handling any kind of service requests in current project in short/allocated period of time with consistent delivery as per the client's expectation.

Excellent communication and presentation skills, vibrant development owner and team player. I am also comfortable working both as a team and individual.

Work Experience

- Tetrasoft as Senior Software Engineer Aug 2009 to Apr 2020
- Tetrasoft as Senior Software Engineer Aug 2009 to Apr 2020

Project. 1

Project Name: WGS - Group Enrollment

Client Well Point Role Software Engineer

Organization Tetrasoft India Pvt Limited, Hyderabad, India

Duration Aug 2009 to Feb 2015

Team Size 8 Environment

Languages: COBOL, JCL, VSAM, DYL280

Database: IMS DB, DB2, CICS

Tools: Xpediter, File Manager, Changeman

Project Description

WGS is the application that WellPoint uses to receive and process their National/Large group accounts Eligibility. The project OH-Group Enrollment is to handle the National Accounts Eligibility. The account that has more than 500 members is called as National Account in WellPoint. Each account sends eligibility file to WellPoint for enrollment in different formats (ANSI 834, Hewitt, Fidelity, Custom etc.) through secured FTP and delivers at WellPoint FTP gateway. The Group Tape Process picks up the file from FTP server and places the file on Mainframe. The subsequent jobs

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

would convert the file into WGS standard format and process the file & loads the membership into WGS. It's an ongoing process. Groups send their eligibility files in frequent intervals that they agreed upon. Responsibilities

Support the Project Lead in delivering the tasks to onsite and client

Allocate and track the tasks given to the developers.

Preparing Unit test plan

Participate in impact analysis review and design document reviews

Coordinate and participate in UTR reviews Complete the assigned tasks on time

Ensure Quality of Deliverables- Components and Documents

Project. 2

Project Name: Arkansas Blue Cross Blue Shield(ARBCBS)

Client Blue Cross Blue Shield

Role Onsite Co-Ordinator and Team Lead

Organization Tetrasoft India Pvt Limited, Hyderabad, India

Duration Feb 2015 to July 2020 (Worked 4 years 6 months at Client location - LITTLE ROCK, ARKANSAS, USA)

Team Size 7 Environment

Languages: COBOL, JCL, VSAM

Database: IMS DB, DB2 ETL Tools: Ab Initio

Tools: Debug Tool, File Manager, Endevor

Project Description

ARBCBS is the application that Blue Cross Blue Shield uses to receive and process their Health Advantage(HA), Blue Advantage(BA) and Blue Cross(BC) Membership and Claims. ARBCBS application will support both Self Insured and Fully Insured clients. The Movelt team picks up the files from vendor locations and places the file on ARBCBS DLZ location. The subsequent jobs would convert the file into a standard format and loads the data into Group, Member and Claims DWH tables.

Responsibilities

Attend the Meetings with the Clients to understand the Requirements.

Do extensive Impact Analysis of the existing Abinitio & Cobol - Code/Copy Books/DML/Other Objects to see how we can incorporate the New Code based off of the existing Code.

Participate in impact analysis review and design document reviews

Allocate and track the tasks given to the developers.

Preparing Unit test plan

Coordinate and participate in UTR reviews

Complete the assigned tasks on time

Ensure Quality of Deliverables- Components and Documents

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from GPulla Reddy Engineering College, Kurnool in 2007

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
OS/390, MVS		
COBOL , JCL, VSAM, DYL280, CICS		
IMS DB, DB2		
Xpeditor, File Aid, File Manager		
Fault Analyzer, Debug Tool, SPUFI		
QMF, Chgman		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - IClClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.